the Magi restoration of the 19th century
had established the Emperor as the
Divine ruler of Japan in theory the
emperor now appointed all senior members
of the military and government and led
the Japanese Armed Forces during times
of war in reality however the emperor
was only a figurehead who wielded little
political power and instead simply
robber stamped the decisions of military
and government officials who had
formulated policies without his input by
the time Emperor hito came to the throne
in 1926 Japanese politics was spiraling
into
chaos Just 4 years into his Reign and
with State Shinto having spread
throughout military acmis the military
had an almost complete Monopoly over
culture and government policy with those
who spoke out against their influence
often finding themselves
assassinated as the decades passed and
the Second World War began this culture
of fear had become the